The most powerful weapon is the truth.
A Private War is a drama, war film directed by Matthew Heineman.
One of the most celebrated war correspondents of our time, Marie Colvin is an utterly fearless and rebellious
spirit, driven to the frontlines of conflicts across the globe to give voice to the voiceless.
Marie Colvin, played by Rosamund Pike.
Paul Conroy, played by Jamie Dornan.
Sean Ryan, played by Tom Hollander.
Tony Shaw, played by Stanley Tucci.
Norm Coburn, played by Corey Johnson.
Professor David Irens, played by Greg Wise.
A Private War is a 2018 American biographical war drama film directed by Matthew
Heineman, and starring Rosamund Pike as journalist Marie Colvin.
The film is based on the 2012 article "Marie Colvin’s
Private War" in Vanity Fair by Marie Brenner.
The film was written by Arash Amel and features Jamie
Dornan, Tom Hollander and Stanley Tucci.
The film premiered at the 2018 Toronto International Film Festival and
was released in the United States on November 2, 2018.
It received positive reviews from critics, who praised Pike's performance.
At the 76th Golden Globe Awards, the film earned nominations for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama (Pike) and Best Original Song ("Requiem for A Private War"), while
director Matthew Heineman received a nomination for Outstanding Directorial Achievement of a First Time Feature Film Director from the Directors Guild of America.
The film explores themes of journalist, palestinian-israeli
conflict, war correspondent, biography, syria.
The tone is emotional.